<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
        <!-- Some useful entities borrowed from HTML -->
        <!ENTITY ndash  "&#x2013;">
        <!ENTITY mdash  "&#x2014;">
        <!ENTITY hellip "&#x2026;">
        
        <!-- Useful for describing APIs -->
        <!ENTITY GET    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">GET</command>'>
        <!ENTITY PUT    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">PUT</command>'>
        <!ENTITY POST   '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">POST</command>'>
        <!ENTITY DELETE '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">DELETE</command>'>
        
        <!-- Product references -->
        
        <!ENTITY CS 'Cloud Servers'>
<!ENTITY HOST 'dfw.servers.api.rackspacecloud.com'>
<!ENTITY URL 'https://&HOST;/v2/'>
]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="ch_install">
    <title>Download Oxygen Author</title>

    <?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
    <para>Download Oxygen Author from the following link: </para>
    <para><link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/oxygen/"
            >http://docs.rackspace.com/oxygen/</link></para>
    <para>On the web start page, click the appropriate link to launch
        the Rackspace/OpenStack edition of SyncRO Soft's &lt;oXygen/>
        XML Editor or Author.</para>
    <para>Use the editor to edit RackBook documents and WADL files. </para>
    <para>The total size of the Java web start bundle is about 87 MBs.
        When you run the application for the first time, Java Web
        Start downloads the entire package, which contains 15 jar
        files. </para>
    <para>When you launch the application again in the future, JWS
        check only for modified jar files (an upgrade) and downloads
        them if necessary. If no new jars are found or network
        connectivity is not available, the application starts
        immediately. Press "Start" when the Java TM Web Start finishes
        the download. Once the application launches, you must supply a
        valid oXygen Editor or Author license. Run &lt;oXygen/>
        Author: Appropriate for editing Rackbook (DocBook) documents
        and WADL files. Run &lt;oXygen/> Editor: Appropriate for
        editing Rackbook (DocBook) documents and WADL files. Also
        includes XSD and XSLT-related features. The download should
        only take a few minutes on a reasonably fast connection. <note>
            <para>If you install oXygen through JWS and then add
                oXygen plugins to that installation, those plugins are
                removed when oXygen is updated.</para>
        </note></para>




</chapter>
