<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
        <!-- Some useful entities borrowed from HTML -->
        <!ENTITY ndash  "&#x2013;">
        <!ENTITY mdash  "&#x2014;">
        <!ENTITY hellip "&#x2026;">
        
        <!-- Useful for describing APIs -->
        <!ENTITY GET    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">GET</command>'>
        <!ENTITY PUT    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">PUT</command>'>
        <!ENTITY POST   '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">POST</command>'>
        <!ENTITY DELETE '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">DELETE</command>'>
        
        <!-- Product references -->
        
        <!ENTITY CS 'Cloud Servers'>
<!ENTITY HOST 'dfw.servers.api.rackspacecloud.com'>
<!ENTITY URL 'https://&HOST;/v2/'>
]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="ch_tag_ref">
    <title>Tags Reference</title>
    <info>
        <raxm:metadata
            xmlns:raxm="http://docs.rackspace.com/api/metadata">
            <raxm:type>concept</raxm:type>
            <raxm:product version="v2">servers</raxm:product>
            <raxm:priority>2</raxm:priority>
        </raxm:metadata>  
    </info>
    <?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
    <para>The next generation Cloud Servers <link
            xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/openstack/"
            >powered by OpenStack</link> is a fast, reliable, and
        scalable cloud compute solution that lets you provision
            <glossterm>server</glossterm>s in the Rackspace cloud in
        minutes. </para>
    <para>Cloud Servers provides the core features of the OpenStack
        Compute <glossterm>API</glossterm> v2 and also deploys certain
        Rackspace extensions. The OpenStack Compute API and the
        Rackspace extensions are known collectively as API v2. </para>
    <para>The simple exercises in this guide help you get started with
        the API v2. </para>
    <para>For each exercise in this guide, you choose one of the
        following methods to make API v2 calls: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">The <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.com/knowledge_center/article/using-python-novaclient-with-the-rackspace-cloud"
                            >nova client</link></emphasis>, with the
                    optional <emphasis role="bold"><link
                            xlink:href="http://rackerhacker.github.com/supernova/"
                            >supernova client</link></emphasis>. We
                    recommend that you use the nova client to run
                    simple commands that make API v2 calls. The
                    optional supernova client lets you use the nova
                    client with multiple OpenStack nova environments.
                    These open-source Python clients run on Linux or
                    Mac OS X systems and are easy to learn and use.
                    You can specify a debug parameter on any nova or
                    supernova command to show the underlying API v2
                    request for the command. This is a good way to
                    become familiar with the API v2 requests. </para>

                
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold"><link
                            xlink:href="http://http://curl.haxx.se/"
                            >cURL</link> commands</emphasis>. If you
                    are familiar with or want to learn cURL commands,
                    choose this method. With cURL, you send HTTP
                    requests with embedded API v2 calls from the
                    command line. The cURL examples in this guide
                    include request bodies that are in JSON format.
</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>If you like, you can use cURL in one example
        and switch to the nova or supernova client in the next
        example. If you choose to use a cURL command for any example,
        you must export the environment variables required to run the
        cURL examples. </para>
    <para>Each example, whether nova client or cURL, points you to the
        next step in the process. </para>
    <para>To use the API v2, it helps to be familiar with
            <glossterm>HTTP</glossterm>/1.1, <glossterm
            baseform="RESTful">ReSTful</glossterm> web services, the
        Rackspace Cloud Servers service, and JSON or XML data
        serialization formats.</para>

    <para>We welcome feedback, comments, and bug reports at <link
            xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.com/support/"
            >http://www.rackspace.com/support/</link>. </para>
  
    
    

</chapter>
